THE LAST FANTASY | TLF HALFCD TeaM
字幕：破烂熊
校对、调轴、格式化：Obster-Y@github
仅供交流  严禁商用
在西伯明翰
At Birmingham East,
选举主任宣布了投票结果
the Returning Officer is declaring the result.
James·George·Hacker：2万1千793票
James George Hacker: 21,793.
Arthur·William·Gaunt：1万9千321票
Arthur William Gaunt: 19,321.
所以在当了这么多年的影子大臣后
So Jim Hacker's back, and after
Hacker又回来了
many years as a Shadow Minister
而且看来肯定
seems almost certain
能在新政府中有一席之地
to get a post in the new Government.
-我到现在都没接到个电话  -谁的电话?
- I haven't had a call yet. - Who from?
-我们的新首相 你以为是谁?  -你等什么呢?
- Our new Prime Minister.  - What do you expect?
车队刚从王宫回来 我在新闻上看到的
The car's only just got back from the Palace.
那随时都会打来了
Any moment now, then.
刚才是谁打过来?
So who was on the phone?
Frank·Wiesel 他马上就过来
Frank Wiesel. He's coming right over.
他干吗不直接搬过来住?
Why doesn't he just move in?
Annie 他是我的政治顾问
Annie, he's my political adviser.
-我依赖他  -你干吗不和他结婚?
- I depend on him. - Why don't you marry him?
亲爱的, 你对事情的反应总是过于强烈
Darling, you do over-react to everything, so.
来了!
Here we are!
Jim·Hacker 是的 哦 是你啊
Jim Hacker... yes. Oh, it's you.
是的, 派对很棒, 不是吗?
Yes, was a good party, wasn't it?
是的 我最后也有点头疼了...
Yes, I've got a bit of a headache, too...
听着, 你介意我等一下再打给你吗?
Look, do you mind if I ring you back.
我在等一个很重要的电话 是的 再见
I'm waiting for a rather important call... bye bye.
斯伯特斯伍德参议员
Alderman Spottiswood.
我希望人们别打电话过来祝贺我
I wish people wouldn't ring to congratulate me.
他们不知道我在等电话吗?
Doesn't they realise I'm waiting for the call.
感觉就像是你要作大臣一样
It's as if you're about to enter the Ministry.
是的 不过关键是哪个大臣
Yes, but which Ministry, that's the point.
这是个玩笑!
It was a joke!
哦 这样啊
Oh, I see.
-你很紧张吗?  -不 我不紧张
- Are you very tense? - No, I'm not.
我只是个不准闹情绪的政治家的妻子
I'm just a politician's wife is not allowed to have feels.
一个快乐的无忧无虑的政治家妻子
A happy carefree politician's wife.
-你在找什么?  -烟  我一根都找不到
- What are you looking for? - A cigarette. I can't find any.
看看烟盒
Try the cigarette box.
-是空的  -吃片安定药
- It's empty. - Take a librium.
我找不到安定片 所以我才找烟
I can't find the librium, that's why I'm looking for a cigarette.
哦 Jim 我受够了 你能不能出去买点?
Oh, Jim, I've had it. Would you pop out and get some?
抱歉 我可不敢离开电话
Sorry, I daren't leave the phone.
听着 如果首相想让你进什么愚蠢内阁的话
Look, if the PM wants you to be in the cabinet,
他就一定会再给你打的 或者你可以给他打
he'll phone back. Or you can phone back.
关键是 我发起过反对首相任职的运动
I ran the campaign against the PM forthe leadership.
-如果我出去了 谁知道呢?  -我可以转话
- If I'm out, well, who knows.  - I could take a message.
来了
There it is.
你好 是的 请讲
Hello... yes, speaking...
哦 是你啊 Michael...
Oh, it's you Michael...
我还没接到电话呢 你接到了吗?
I haven't had a call, have you had a call?
比尔接到电话了?
Bill's had a call?
他得到什么差事了? 欧洲?
What's he got? Europe?
-Bill得了欧洲  -幸运的欧洲
- Bill's got Europe. - Lucky Europe.
-Bill会说法语吗?  -他连英语都说不好
- Does Bill speak French?  - He can hardly speak English.
我一有消息就给你打过去 好的  再见
I'll call you back if I hear anything. Right... Bye.
祈祷吧
Fingers crossed.
你好 是的 请讲
Hello... Yes, speaking...
气暖部
The Gas Board.
上帝啊 那都是几周前的事了
Good Lord man, that was weeks ago.
你不介意的话 我在等一个很重要的电话
Would you mind I'm waiting for a rather important call...
听着 Franklin 昨天有一个选举
Look, Franklin there happened to be a general election yesterday...
哦 你投的是另一方 是吗?
You voted for the otherside, did you?
你居然能在正确的日期找到投票点?
How did you get to the polling booth on the right day?
带着两个助手 来回跑了三次找空位?
With two assistants, three return visits for spare parts?
听着 Franklin先生... 事实上 Franklin
Look, Mr. Franklin... Frankly Franklin,
我才不关心整个取暖系统会不会垮掉
I don't care if the whole central heating system collapses in ruins.
我必须要挂电话了  再见
I've got to get off this phone, goodbye.
他们现在不会过来
They won't come now.
如果我去了消费者事务部 他们就会来了
If I get Consumer Affairs, they'll come.
你好?
Hello?
喂?  喂?
Hello? Hello?
亲爱的 是门铃响
Darling, that was the front doorbell.
应该是Frank
It'll be Frank.
-你知道Martin得了外交部吗?  -真的吗?
- Did you know Martin's got the Foreign Office. - Has he?
Jack得了卫生部 Fred得了资源部
Jack's got Health and Fred's got Energy.
-有人得了大脑吗?  -你是说教育部吗?
- Has anyone got Brains? - Do you mean Education?
不是 我知道我什么意思
No, I know what I mean.
-还剩下什么了?  我还有什么?  -韵律?
- What's left? What have I got?  - Rhythm?
Frank 我一点消息都没有
Frank, I have heard absolutely nothing,
一点也不奇怪
not that it's surprising.
我的职业开始走下坡路
My whole career is going down the drain
因为首相打不进我的电话
because the PM is unable to reach me on the telephone.
你接吧 亲爱的
You get it, darling.
-你好  -你好 这是BBC
- Hello. - Hello, this is the BBC.
不知Hacker先生是否愿意在今天
Would Mr. Hacker like to be
下午接收我们的PM(Primetime黄金时间)节目的访问?
interviewed on the PM program this afternoon?
(注：PM是首相Prime Minister的缩写)
- PM? - PM?
这是Jim·Hacker
Jim Hacker here...
你今天下午有空吗?
Are you available this afternoon?
是的 什么时间都可以
Yes. Any time you like.
我们可以采访你吗?
Could we interview you?
我一直在等您的电话
I'd been hoping you'd call.
你认为你会得到什么职位?
What job do you think you're likely to get?
请您再说一遍?
I beg your pardon?
你觉得你可能会得到哪个职位?
What job do you think you're likely to get?
这不是我能决定的 不是吗? 应该是你告诉我
It's hard for me to say, isn't it? That's for you to tell me.
-什么?  -这不是我决定的事啊
- What? - Well, it's not up to me to say.
应该是PM决定的 你是PM办公室的...
That's for the PM to say. You're the PM's office...
哦 我知道了 是BBC的PM办公室
Oh, I see. The BBC PM office!
多傻 多傻的误会啊 是的 是的 再见
How silly, what a silly mistake, Yes... yes. Good bye.
我试着告诉过你了
I did try and tell you.
你去接这该死的东西
You answer the bloody thing.
你好
Hello...
我是Hacker夫人
Mrs. Hacker speaking.
哦 恭喜您 首相  我是安妮
Oh, congratulations, "Prime Minister". It's Annie here.
给我电话
Give me that phone.
你好 是的 首相
Hello... Yes... Prime Minister.
是的 当然了 是的 我...
Yes, of course... Yes, I...
好的
Righto.
我会坐下一班火车的
I'll be on the next train.
行政部的一把手是Jim·Hacker
Top tip for The Department of Administrative Affairs is Jim Hacker.
肯尼思 他对于内阁职位来说 难道不是很年轻吗?
Kenneth, isn't he on the young side for a Cabinet post?
是啊 不过 他已经快步入五十了
Yes, well, he's in his late forties.
不过这对于他来说绝对是一个飞跃
But it's certainly a jump up for him.
话又说回来 这个部门最近
On the otherhand, this department's been
已经快成为政治坟墓了
a bit of a political graveyard recently.
唐宁街10号（首相府）宣布了一组
A further group of Cabinet appointments
新的内阁职位
has now been announced from Number Ten.
行政部大臣的职位给了Jim·Hacker
The post of the Ministry of Administrative Affairs goes to Jim Hacker,
原影子内阁农业大臣
the former Shadow Minister for Agricultura.
-下午好 大臣  -下午好
- Good afternoon, Minister.  - Good afternoon.
Bernard·Wooley 首席私人秘书
Bernard Wooley, Principal Private Secretary.
Lloyd·Pritchard先生 副私人秘书
Mr. Lloyd Pritchard, Assistant Private Secretary.
这是我的政治顾问...
This is my political adviser...
哦是的 当然了 Weasel先生
Oh yes, of course, Mr. Weasel.
Wiesel
Wiesel.
(行政部)
D.A.A.
我是上届大臣的
I was the Minister's Principal Private Secretary
首席私人秘书
in the last goverment.
不过如果你想...
However if you...
我相信你会胜任的
I'm sure you'll be just the thing.
非常感谢 大臣 您真是仁慈
Thank you, Minister, how kind.
-我们这是要去哪?  -现在是去你的办公室
-  Where are we all going to? - You are going to your office.
Frank呢?
What about Frank?
-Frank呢?  -他会被安排好的
- Where's Frank? - He's being taken care of.
-你可以在这里等着吗?  -这是等待室
- Would you wait here? - This is the Waiting Room.
-非常正确 先生  -我是Jim·Hacker的特别顾问
- Precisely, sir. - I'm Jim Hacker's adviser.
他现在有整个部门来做他顾问了
He has a whole department to advise him.
-他需要我  -当然了
- He needs me. - Of course.
不过在他叫你之前 请在这里等着
But until he sends for you, please, wait.
来杯雪利酒 大臣?
A sherry, Minister?
Jim
Jim.
哦 杜松子酒
Oh Gin.
不 不 Jim Jim 叫我Jim好了
No, no, Jim, Jim. Call me Jim.
我想如果对于您来说都是一样的话
I think if it means all the same to you,
我还是更愿意叫你大臣，大臣
I would prefer to call you Minister, Minister.
大臣 大臣?
Minister, Minister?
哦 是的 是的  我明白你的意思了
Oh quite, quite. I see what you mean.
我需要叫你私人助理 私人助理?
Do I have to call you Private Secretary, Private Secretary?
-不 请叫我 Bernard  -谢谢 Bernard
- No. Do call me Bernard.    - Thank you, Bernard.
请不要客气，为你的健康 大臣
You're most welcome. Your health, Minister.
那 接下来是什么?
Well what now?
大臣 请允许我介绍 Humphrey·Appleby 爵士
Minister Allow me to present Sir Humphrey Appleby,
常务次长以及行政事务部的负责人
Permanent UnderSecretary of State and Head of the D.A.A.
-你好 Humphrey爵士  -你好 欢迎
- Hello, Sir Humphrey. - Hello, and welcome.
-谢谢  -我相信你们认识对方
- Thank you. - I believe you know each other.
是的 我们的确在公共账目委员会上交锋过
Yes, we did cross swords in the Public Accounts Committee.
我可不会这么说
I wouldn't say that.
你问了所有我不希望任何人问的问题
You came up with all the questions I hope nobody would ask.
对手就是要提问的
Opposition's about asking questions.
而政府就选择不回答他们
And Government's about not answering them.
不管怎样 你回答了我所有的问题
You answered all mine, anyway.
我很高兴你这样想 大臣
I'm glad you thought so, Minister.
祝你好运
Good luck.
-还有谁在这个部门?  -我是常务次长
- Who else is in this Department? - I am the Permanent UnderSecretary
也就是常任秘书
of the State known as the Permanent Secretary.
Wolley是你的首席私人秘书
Wolley is your Principal Private Secretary.
而我也有一个首席私人秘书
And I too have a Principal Private Secretary.
而他是常任秘书的首席私人秘书
And he is the Principal Private Secretary to the Permanent Secretary
直接受我管辖的有十个常务副秘书长
Directly responsible to me are 10 Deputy Secretaries
87个副秘书长和219个秘书助理
87 UnderSecretaries, and 219 Assistant Secretaries.
直接受首席私人秘书管辖的
Directly Responsible to the PPS
是国会私人秘书
are Parliamentary Private Secretaries.
首相会给你指定两个国会私人秘书
The PM will be appointing two Parliamentary UnderSecretaries,
然后你会指定你自己的国会私人秘书
and you will appoint your own Parliamentary Private Secretary.
他们都会打字吗?
Can they all type?
我们没一个会打字 大臣
None of us can type, Minister.
麦肯夫人打字
Mrs. McKay types.
她是秘书
She is the Secretary.
真可惜 我们都能开个代理处了
Pity we could have opened an agency.
-非常幽默 先生  -是的 非常非常有趣
- Very droll, sir.    - Yes, very very amusing.
-我想他们都这么说  -当然不是 大臣
- I suppose they all say that. - Certainly not, Minister.
并不是这样
Not quite all.
对 现在该谈正事了
Right, now then, to business.
如果我太迟钝了请你们原谅
You have to forgive me if I'm a bit blunt,
不过我就是这种人...
but that's the sort of chap I am...
看起来 这个部...
Frankly, this depart...
这个椅子有点...
This chair's a bit...
我们可以换一个 大臣
We can change it, Minister.
我们可以换任何东西 大臣
We can change anything, Minister.
家具 装饰品 办公惯例...
The furniture, decor, office routine...
-悉听尊便  -我想要一个新的椅子
- Your wish is our command. - I'd like a new chair.
我讨厌旋转椅
I hate swivel chairs.
人们的确说两种大臣
They do say that there are two kinds of chairs
就有两种对应的椅子
to go with the two kinds of Minister.
一种雷厉风行
One sort folds up instantly,
另一种原地转圈
the other sort goes round and round in circles.
好了 先生们 看来这个部门必须
Now, frankly this Department has got to cut
冲破紧绑的官僚体制的束缚
a great swathe through all this stuffy Whitehall bureaucracy.
我们要打开窗子
We're going to throw open the windows,
换些新鲜空气 免去所有的繁文缛节
let in a bit of fresh air, cut through all the red tape,
让这台嘎吱作响的旧官僚机器重焕活力
streamline this creaking old bureaucratic machine.
-你是说一个大扫除?  -就是一个大扫除
- You mean a clean sweep? - A clean sweep.
太多的人就只是坐在桌子后面
Far too many people just sitting behind desks.
当然不是像我们这样了
Not like us, of course.
不过我们必须清除给彼此制造工作的人了
But we've got to get rid of all those people just making work for each other.
-清除掉?  -我想您是说重新部署他们?
- Get rid of them? - I think you mean "Redeploy them".
是的 哦上帝 不 我不是说让他们下岗
Yes. Good Lord no, I don't mean put them out of work.
透明政府 是我的政党的信条
Open Government, that's what my party believes in,
是我们宣言的主要纲领
that was the main plank of our manifesto.
让我们充分相信国家
Taking the nation into our confidence.
这让你耳目一新? 请坐
Now how does that strike you? Do sit down.
事实上 就像你在去年5月2号在议会
In fact, Just as you said in the House on May 2nd last year,
然后是11月23号
and again on November 23rd,
然后在《观察者日报》和《每日邮报》
and in The Observer and in The Daily Mail,
和你的宣言所说的那样
and as your manifesto made clear.
这你都知道?
You know about that?
请看看这些提议 大臣
Please, have a look at these proposals Minister.
这些是使这个政策生效的大体规划
These are the ways to implement this policy
和一个需要你通过的白皮书
and proposals for a white paper for your approval.
那张白皮书就可以叫做"透明政府"
The white paper might be called "Open Government".
-你是说一切都...  -处理好了 大臣
- You mean it's all been... - Taken care of, Minister.
-谁做的这些?  -那台嘎吱作响的旧官僚机器
- Who did all this? - The old bureaucratic machine.
不 说正经的
No, quite seriously.
我们已经为重组做好准备了
We are fully seized of the need for reform.
-而且我们已经提出这个议题了  -我真的很惊讶
- And we have taken it on board. - I'm rather surprised.
我还以为需要不停的说服你们呢
I expected to have to fight you all the way along the line with this.
人们对于公务员的确是有一些有趣的看法
People do have funny ideas about the Civil Service.
我们只是来帮助执行您的政策的
We're just here to implement your policies.
"缩短申请上诉手续的提案"?
"Proposals for shortening approval procedures in planning appeals"?
英国国会议事录 第487卷 第1102页 B栏
Hansard Volume 497, page 1102, Column B.
引自 Hacker先生：
Quote "Mr. Hacker:
“首相是否知道计划所花的程序
Is the Minister aware that planning procedures
使得在20世纪建一栋平房比
make building a bungalow in the 20th century
在12世纪建一栋大教堂还要慢?
slower than building a cathedral in the 12th century?
对手党在狂笑 政府因羞愧而哭泣”
Opposition laughter and Government cries of shame".
他们并没有真的因羞愧而哭泣
They didn't actually cry shame.
的确如此 大臣
Quite so, Minister.
-好吧 我想应该就这些了吧?  -还有一两件事情...
- Right, I think that's it then? - There are one or two more things...
还有事?
One more thing?
如果您能看看下周的行程表 大臣
If you would just like to check your diary for next week, Minister.
我的行程表? 你又不知道我会来
My diary? You didn't know I was coming.
你甚至都不知道谁会赢得选举
You didn't even know who'd win the election.
我们知道会有一个大臣 大臣
We knew there'd be a Minister, Minister.
又来了
Don't start that again.
很抱歉 尽管我们不知道那会是你
I'm sorry, even though we didn't know it would be you.
女王殿下的确希望政府
Her Majesty does like the business of government
能够继续运转 即使没有政治家
to continue even when there are no politicians around.
-一定很难啦?  -的确...也不是
- Bit difficult surely? - Yes... and no.
接下来会是很繁忙的一周 大臣 有九个内阁委员会
It's gonna be quite a busy week, Minister. Nine cabinet committees,
星期一八点钟 在法律协会的年度晚会
the Annual dinner of the Law Institute On Monday at 8:00,
你要发表讲话
which you will have to make a speech.
星期二早上十点半
Deputation from the British Computer Association,
会见英格兰电脑协会的代表团
10:30 Tuesday morning.
星期三十一点
Opening the National Union of Public Employers meeting
开始国家公众雇主工会的会议
at 11:00 on Wednesday,
到时你还需要再做一个演讲...
which you will have to make another speech...
等等 等一下
Wait Wait a minute...
那我要做的其他事情该怎么办?
What about all the other things I have to do?
什么其它的事情?
What otherthings?
我的政党有四个委员会需要我参加
I'm on four policy committees for the party for a start.
我相信您不想把政党放在国家的前面 大臣
I'm sure you won't want to be putting party before country, minister.
不 不 当然不了
No, no, of course not.
我去拿你的档案盒 大臣
I'll just fetch your boxes, Minister.
档案盒? 已经开始了吗?
Boxes? Already.
竞选时 我们保留了上一届大臣所作的工作
We get manage to keep the last Minister's work throughout the campaign,
不过我恐怕...这轮不到我去评论
but I fear... well, it's not for me to criticise...
-这是什么意思?  -听起来很刺耳
- What do you mean? - It's a harsh thing to say.
不过有些档案盒带着未完成的工作又回来了
Some of the boxes actually came back with the work not done.
如果你在周六晚之前完成前四个的话
If you complete the first four by Saturday evening,
你的司机就会收走他们并把剩下的两个带来
your driver could collect them and deliver the other two.
Villa在家等着去利物浦
Villa's at home to Liverpool.
而且我星期六有个手术要做
And I've got a surgery on Saturday.
我们可以减少一些书面工作
We could minimise the paper work,
你只要做一些主要的政策决定就好
you need only take the major policy decisions.
不不不不 这儿所有的决定都由我来定
No, no. No. No. I will take all the decisions round here.
那我星期一什么时候来?
Now then what time shall I come in on Monday?
你要在新街坐7点45的火车 大臣
You'll catch the 7.45 train from New Street, Minister,
-然后你的司机会在尤斯登接你  -很好
- and your driver will meet you at Euston. - Fine.
让我把这些提议的草稿放进去
If I could just put in these draft proposals.
然后给 这是您的钥匙 大臣
And here, this is yourkey, Minister.
走开 我已经受够了
Out of my way. I've had enough of this.
-你不能进去  -那你就拦我试试看
- You can't go in there. - Just try and stop me.
-Jim 这到底是怎么回事?  -Frank 你去哪了?
- Jim, what's going on? - Frank, where've you been?
被关在等待室里
Stuck in the waiting room.
对不起 我们正在和大臣进行私人会议
Do you mind? We are in a private conference with the minister.
-那我也应该在这里  -冷静点 Frank
- Then I should be here, too. - Calm down, Frank.
Humphrey, Frank在这个部门必须有一个自己的办公室
Humphrey, Frank has got to have an office of his own in the department.
-当然了 如果你坚持的话  -我坚持
- Certainly, if you insist. - I do insist.
我相信我们在沃森斯道(偏远地区)还有些空办公室
I do think we have some spare office space in Walthamstow.
-沃森斯道?  -是啊 真让人惊喜
- Walthamstow? - Yes, it's surprising.
政府掌握伦敦所有的地产
The Government owns property all over London.
-我不想在沃森斯道  -那地方在一个很好的地区
- I don't want to be in Walthamstow. - It's in a very nice part.
据我所知沃森斯道是个很棒的地方
Walthamstow's a very nice place so I gather.
-我需要在这个楼里有个办公室  -为什么?
- I need an office here in this building. - Why's that?
是的　我同意Frank
Yes, I agree with Frank.
Bernard，我们必须给Weasel先生在这儿找间办公室
Bernard, we must find an office here for Mr. Weasel.
Wiesel.
所有给我的文件都要给Frank复印一份
Copies of all the papers that come to me go to Frank.
-所有的?  -所有的
- All?  - All.
没问题
It shall be done.
所有适当的文件
All the appropriate papers.
你的新大臣怎么样 Humphrey?
How's your new Minister, Humphrey?
以一个新人来说学得的很快
Learning the rules very quickly for a newboy.
-你的新内阁怎么样?  -没问题
- How's your new Cabinet? - No problem.
很难找出和上一届有什么不同
It's hard to tell the differece with the last one.
Arnold, 我听说最近美国的大使
Arnold, I hear the American Ambassador's been spending
经常和首相在一起
a lot of time with the PM.
-是的  -有敌意的还是友好的?
- Yes. - Defence or trade?
两者都有
Both.
那个航天系统的合同?
The aerospace systems contract?
暂时别让内阁听到
Ssh. Don't want the cabinet to hear about it yet.
这个 航空的东西对于首相来讲
This aerospace thingumy would be
应该算是一个妙举 是吗?
rather a coup for the PM, wouldn't it?
是的 现在新首相可以赢得声望了
Yes, now the new PM will take the credit.
很抱歉打扰了 Arnold先生 Humphrey先生
Sorry to intrude Sir Arnold, Sir Humphrey,
如果你能过一下大臣的演讲稿
if you could just OK the Minister's speech,
我就可以把它给议会了
I can get it straight to the House.
好的 当然可以 想加入我们吗?
Yes, of course. Like to join us?
哦 谢谢 Humphrey先生 不过我现在很忙
Oh, thank you, Sir Humphrey, so long as I'm not too long.
给你自己弄杯咖啡吧
Get yourself a cup of coffee.
所以这对首相来说就应该是个羞耻了
So it would be rather an embarrassment to the PM,
不是吗?  如果一个爱幻想的大臣
wouldn't it? if a hypothetical Minister were to rock
想要掀翻英国和美国人的船?
the Anglo American boat?
绝对的羞耻
Grave embarrassment.
多么绝对?
How grave?
我想会是人仰马翻
Man overboard, I should think.
足够缩短一个前途美好的大臣的职业生涯了?
Enough to cut short a promising new Ministerial career?
没有问题
No question.
坐下吧 Bernard
Pull up a chair, Bernard...
说一说你对我们的新大臣的看法
And tell us what you think of our new Minister.
非常不错
Well absolutely fine.
是的 我们会马上就培训好他的
Yes, we'll have him housetrained in no time.
他把整个日程都囫囵吞下了
He swallowed the whole diary,
我想他上周废寝忘食的完成所有的档案盒了?
and I gatherhe did his boxes like a lamb lastweekend?
是的 他都完成了
Yes. Yes he did.
我们必须让他忘掉透明政府这种瞎话
We must head him off this Open Government nonsense.
我以为那些白皮书的名字就是"透明政府"
I thought we were calling the White Paper "Open Government".
是 我们总把难的部分放到题目里
Always dispose of the difficult bit in the title.
放那里比放到文章里要无害多了
Does less harm there than in the text.
你越不想做什么事情
The less you intend to do about something,
就越会不断地说这件事
the more you have to keep talking about it.
不过, "透明政府"有什么不对吗?
What's wrong with open government?
为什么公众不能对正在发生的事知道的更详细些?
Why shouldn't the public know more about what's going on?
你当真吗?
Are you serious?
是啊 我是说 这毕竟是大臣的政策
Well, yes, I mean it's the Minister's policy, afterall.
这个短语本来就互相矛盾
It's a contradiction in terms.
你可以是透明或者你可以有个政府
You can be open or you can have government.
不过 民主政府的公民们当然有权利了解
But surely the citizens of a democracy have a right to know.
不 他们有无知的权利
No. They have a right to be ignorant.
知识代表着阴谋和罪行
Knowledge only means complicity and guilt.
无知倒有一定的尊严
Ignorance has a certain dignity.
不过如果大臣想要这个"透明政府"
But if the Minister wants...
你不能只是让人得其所愿
You don't just give people what they want,
要是这对他们并无好处的话
if it's not good for them.
你会给一个酒鬼白兰地吗?
Do you give brandy to an alcoholic?
如果人们不知道你在干什么
If people don't know what you are doing,
他们就不知道你做错了什么
they don't know what you are doing wrong.
抱歉 先生们 我是大臣的私人秘书 如果他想...
I am the Minister's Private Secretary, and if he wants...
你总不能帮着我们的大臣让他出丑吧
You must not help him to make a fool of himself.
看看我们以往的那些大臣
Look at the Ministers we've had.
要不是他们死命地保住了秘密
Everyone of them would have been a laughing stock in three month
不用三个月就成了别人的笑柄了
had it not been for the most rigid secrecy about what they were up to.
那你有什么建议呢?
What do you propose to do?
-你能保守秘密吗?  -当然了
- Can you keep a secret? - Of course.
我也能
So can I.
请原谅 我得去打个电话
Excuse me, I have to make a phone call.
我最好把这个还给大臣了
Well, I'd better be getting this back to the Minister.
马丁·威瑟尔有没有拿到
Martin. Has the weasel had a copy of the invoice
新的美国寻址机器的发票复印件?
for the new American addressing machines?
我以为您说那个是机密文件
I thought you said it was sensitive.
的确是这样  今天给他看吧
So it is. Get it to him today.
哦 还有马丁 让他在一摞文件的底部看到它
Oh, and Martin, let him find it near the bottom of the pile.
Jim Jim
Jim, Jim.
-怎么了  -看看我找到了什么
- Yes. - Look what I've found.
-我们这次可抓到他们的小辫子了  -你说什么呢?
- We've got them by the short and curlies. - What're you talking about?
我们抓到 Humphrey·Appleby
We've got Sir Humphrey Bloody Appleby
和太妃糖鼻子 自大的Wolley先生的把柄了
and Mr. Toffee Nosed Snooty Wolley
就在我们想要抓的地方 看这个
just where we want them. See this?
这张看起来很无辜的纸
This innocent-looking piece of paper.
这个政治炸药
Political dynamite.
冷静点  我都不明白你到底在说什么
Calm down. What are you talking about?
这是个一千个监控显示设备终端机的发票
This is an invoice for 1.000 computer video display terminals.
每个一万英镑 也就是总共一千万英镑
At 10.000 pounds each, that is, ten milion pounds.
然后呢?
So?
是匹兹堡制造公司生产的
Made by the Pittsburgh Manufacturing Corporation Inc.,
-从美国进口的?  -是啊
- Imported from America? - I know.
但是我们自己也制造电脑外围设备
But we make computer peripherals in this country.
-就在我自己的选区啊  -就是啊!
- In my constituency. - I know!
-失业问题怎么办?  -就是啊!
- What about unemployment? - I know!
我必须阻止它
This must be stopped.
-Humphrey先生想...哦 对不起  -哦 不 不 进来
- Sir Humphrey to see... oh sorry.     - Oh no. No, come in.
我想见你们两个 快进来
I want to see you both, come on.
Humphrey先生 请坐
Sir Humphrey, take a seat.
谢谢 大臣
Thank you, Minister.
Frank刚刚发现这个关于
Now then, Frank here has just discovered this contract
从美国那里购入价值一千万英镑的
for the import of ten million pound's worth
监视终端的合同
of video display terminals, from America.
我能看一下吗?
May I see?
哦 是的  给白厅的公务员用的
Oh yes. For the whole Civil Service in Whitehall.
-不过这些东西不是英国的  -很不幸 是的
- But they're not British. - That is unfortunately true.
-我们的国家也生产这些东西  -不是同样的质量
- We make these machines in this country. - Not of the same quality.
更好的质量  在我的选区
Better quality. In my constituency.
-我们被告知...  -这个合同必须被阻止
- We were advised...      - This contract must be stopped.
这不在我的权力之内了 大臣 只有财政部才能取消
It's beyond my power, Minister. This can only be cancelled by the Treasury.
为什么?
Why's that?
公务方面关于取消合同有了一个
Would be a major policy change for the Civil Service
重要的政策改变 尤其是海外的合同
to cancel contracts, especially with overseas suppliers.
也许你想和内阁提一下这件事情
If you'd like to take it up with the Cabinet.
我该怎么面对我的政党?
How am I to face my constituency party?
为什么他们需要知道?
Why need they know?
为什么要别人知道?
Why need anybody know?
我们当作什么都没发生
We can see that it never gets out.
-透明政府  -对啊 透明政府
- Open Government. - That's right.Open Government.
如果这个合同不能被取消 那它就应该被公开
If the order can't be cancelled, it must be published.
正确  应该公开它
That's right. It must be published.
为什么?
Why?
-为什么 Frank?  -宣言
- Why, Frank?     - The manifesto.
而且会让你的前任看起来像个叛徒
Also it will make your predecessor look like a traitor.
-对 两个无法忽视的原因  -这事不能讨价还价!
- Two unanswerable reasons.     - You didn't bargain for this!
你不会是在建议让
You're not suggesting
大臣在演讲里把这个机密的
that the Minister should make a positive reference
交易作为正面参考吧?
to this confidential transaction in a speech?
演讲  就是这个
Speech. That's it.
Jim 那个国家公众雇主工会的会议的演讲怎么样?
Jim, what about the speech to the Union of office Employees?
我会告诉他们这个可耻的合同
I'll tell them about this scandalous contract.
而且我们今天就要发布出去
And we'll release it to the press today.
-现在是谁在管理国家了?  -啊...是的
- Who's running the country now? - Well... yes.
-你反对?  -如果我们惹恼美国人的话
- You object?  - It might be regrettable,
-也许事情会很难办  -美国人
- if we upset the Americans. - The Americans.
是他们丢掉他们自满的经济态度的时候了
It's time they lose their commercial complacency.
-我们必须关心英国的穷人 不是美国的富人  -对!
- We must think of the British poor, not the American rich!  - Right
如果那是您的直接指令的话
If that is your express wish,
整个部门都会支持你的 全力以赴
the Departmentwill back you, up to the hilt.
那是我的直接指令
That is my express wish.
我最好把演讲稿给有关部门请求通过
I'd better circulate the speech to the relevant department for clearance.
通过?  和别的部门又没关系
Clearance? It got nothing to do with other department.
透明政府要求我们应该和我们的同事
Open Government demands that we should include our colleagues,
以及我们富利特街上的朋友一起共事
as well as our friends in Fleet Street.
-哦是的 的确是这样  -我可不确定
- Oh yes, that's fair enough. - I'm not sure.
谢谢你们  还有 Humphrey...
Thank you. And Humphrey...
要把它直接交给媒体
See that goes straight to the press.
我们会履行您的要求
We shall serve your best interests.
谢谢
Thank you.
那么...
Now then...
我看看
Let me see.
透明政府
Open Government.
我们保证人们会给他们一个透明政府
As you know, We've made a pledge to the people about open government.
那就开始吧
So let's have some.
我了解到就在上个月 上一届政府
I have discovered that only last month, the previous government
签了一份一千万英镑的进口合同
signed a contract to import 10,000 pounds of office equipment
-用于公务员的办公室用品...  -官僚!
- to used by the Civil Service... - Bureaucracy!
提供给公务官僚的用品
Used by the Civil Service bureaucracy.
所以 我们被美国匹兹堡聪明的
So, we are being fobbed off with second rate American junk
推销员用二等货给欺骗了
by smart Aleck salesmen from Pittsburgh
而英国的工厂却歇业
while British factories stand empty
英国的工人排着长队领施舍品
and British workmen queue up for the dole.
-失业救济金  -施舍品 Bernard
- Unemployment benefit.    - The dole, Bernard.
"这就是我对咱们大洋对面
"Much as I personally value the friendship of our great cousins
了不起的表弟的看法"
from across the sea".
-打扰一下 大臣 有点事情  -什么事?
- Excuse me Minister, something's come up. - Yes?
-是首相那里的事情  -我很忙
- A minute from the PM's Office. - I'm pretty busy.
-我想你必须看一下 大臣  -那上面写了些什么?
- I do think you ought to read this, Minister. - What does it say?
首相打算下个月访问华盛顿
The PM is planning a visit to Washington next month
讨论一个价值不菲的英美安防贸易合约
for a valuable Anglo American defence trade agreement.
其重要性不可小觑
Its importance cannot be overestimated.
好啊  天哪 我的演讲已经给媒体了吗?
Fine. God Has my speech gone to the press?
我想是的 按照您的要求
I presume so, as you requested.
很抱歉 不过首相府已经乱套了
I'm sorry, but all hell's just broken loose at Number Ten.
他们问为什么你的演讲未经审查
They're asking why your speech didn't obtain clearance.
-你怎么回答的?  -我说我们相信透明政府
- What did you say?     - I said we believed in open government.
不过看起来只让事情变的更糟
But it seemed to make things worse.
首相希望在议会见您 马上
The PM wants to see you in the House, right away.
会发生什么?
What's going to happen?
水能载舟 亦能覆舟
The Prime Minister giveth and the Prime Minister taketh away.
祝福首相
Blessed be the name of the Prime Minister.
你好 维克...
Hello, Vic...
Humphrey·Appleby  Vic·Gould 我们的首席组织秘书
Sir Humphrey Appleby, Vic Gould, our Chief Whip.
你真是会惹麻烦啊 是吗?
You really are a pain in the ass, aren't you?
首相都快跳墙了
The PM's going up the wall.
以头抢地了
Hitting the roof.
你不能随便发表那样的演讲
You can't go around making speeches like that.
这是个透明政府
It's Open Government.
-闭嘴 Weasel 谁问你了  -Wiesel!
- Shut up, Weasel. - Wiesel!
不过透明政府是我们宣言的主要纲领
But Open Government was the main plank in our manifesto.
-首相也是这么认为的  -透明 是的  不过不是裂个大洞
- The PM believes in it too. - Open, yes. But not gaping.
搞政治就要学会怎样机智的说话 傻瓜!
In politics you have to learn say things with tact, you berk!
还有什么时候不应该说话
And when to say nothing at all.
-你当大臣多长时间了?  -一周半了
- How long have you been a Minister? - Week and half.
也许你能进吉尼斯纪录了
I think You may find a place in the Guinness book of records.
我已经能看到标题了
I can see the headlines already.
"内阁在美国贸易问题上产生分歧
"Cabinet split on U.S. Trade.
Hacker发起对首相的叛变"
Hacker leads revolt against Prime Minister.
这就是你想要的 是不是?
That's what you want, is it?
Arnold爵士 有什么新消息吗?
Ah, Sir Arnold, what news?
那个演讲让首相很焦虑
That speech is causing the PM some distress.
它确实已经捅到媒体那里了吗?
Has it definitely been released to the Press?
大臣是在中午下达的直接指令
Well, the Minister gave express instructions for noon.
-不是吗?  -你真是让我惊骇 Humphrey
- Isn't that right? - I'm appalled at you, Humphrey.
你怎么能让首相在甚至没上电视的情况下
How could you let the Minister put himself in this position
就置身于这样糟的状况?
without gonig to the public channel?
我们相信透明政府
We believe in open government.
我们想打开窗户 透进一些新鲜空气
We want to open the windows and let in a bit of fresh air.
不是吗 大臣?
Isn't that right, Minister?
这对政党来说是个好口号
It's good party stuff,
但是这让首相很难堪
but it puts the PM in a very difficult situation.
那我们对透明政府做出的承诺呢?
What about our commitment to Open Government?
看起来这已经是透明政府的最后一季了
This seems to be the closed season for open government.
你要不要考虑一下
Do you want to give thought
写辞呈的草稿?
to a draft letter of resignation?
以防万一...
Just in case...
我们不能把它遮掩过去吗?
Can't we hush it up?
-遮掩?  -是的 遮掩过去
- Hush it up?  - Yes, hush it up.
你是说...把消息压下去?
You mean... suppress it?
是的 就这个意思
Yes, I suppose I do.
你的意思是说 在你安排的
You mean that within the framework of the guidelines
透明政府的指引方针内
about open goverment that you have laid down,
你建议我们应该采用一个更灵活的态度?
you're suggesting we should adopt a more flexible posture?
我是这个意思吗?  哦 是的 是的
Am I? Oh yes. Yes.
大臣 关于记者会...
Minister about the press release...
我们似乎还有
There appears to be a development
回转的余地
could precipitate a reappraisal of our position.
我们忘了各部间的审查过程
We forgot the interdepartmental clearance procedure.
附加阻止令起效用了
The supplementary stop order came into effect.
所以 你的演讲还没捅给媒体
So, your speech hasn't gone to the Press.
它只是捅到了首相的私人办公室
It's only gone to the PM's Private Office
而没有首相和外交部的指示
and the Duty Officer had no instructions to pass it out
-行动事务员没有把它公布  -不过为什么呢?
- without clearance of the PM and the foreign office. - But how come?
这全都是我的错 大臣
The fault is entirely mine, Minister.
这个阻止公布演讲的程序是在
The procedure of the holding up of press releases dates back to
确立透明政府之前的事情了
before open government,
我不知为什么忘了废除它了
and I unaccountably omitted to rescind it.
-我希望你能原谅我的过失  -哦 当然了
- I hope you forgive this lapse. - Well, yes, of course.
-当然没问题了  -谢谢 大臣
- That's quite all right. - Thank you, Minister.
毕竟 我们都会犯错误
Afterall, we all make mistakes.
是 大臣
Yes, Minister.